<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Icy Seas Co-Lab</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Icy Seas Co-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Thomas Bryce Kelly, 2025 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:25:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common Image Formats Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-image-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:25:00 -1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-image-formats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a recent conversation with a friend about photography and digital images, there seems to be many unanswered questions out there regarding the wide variety of image formats which have become commonplace in our lives. A few months ago I wrote a short article on HDR Photography (link) since so many people were asking questions about that setting on their iPhone. In a similar vein, I hope to build a practical foundation so you know when and why you would like the image to be saved as png, jpg, pdf etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Founding Icy Seas Co-Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-founding-icyseas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:50:58 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2025-founding-icyseas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;strong&gt;Icy Seas Co-Lab&lt;/strong&gt; has been around in one form or another for the past couple of years, just recently we decided to take the full step of incorporating into &lt;em&gt;Icy Seas Co-Laboratory LLC&lt;/em&gt;. We did this for two reasons: adaptability and teamwork. By distancing ourselves from university activities, we gain &lt;strong&gt;adaptability&lt;/strong&gt; with respect to the projects we take on, the timeframe between project start and project conclusion, and allow for a wider variety of services. Similarly we find that Icy Seas Co-Laboratory can be a &lt;strong&gt;better partner&lt;/strong&gt; and be more responsive to colleagues, clients, and community members as a primary business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
